We're going now.
Haruto, watch out above you!
Rio...
Spirit Chronicles 2
Could I attend the party in Galarc
where the Heroes will be introduced?
My travel companions and I... wish
to meet Dame Sumeragi Satsuki.
It's over.
We can release our magic here, too.
R-Right!
Haruto is just fine.
Aishia...
Toward a Fateful Tomorrow
They got away.
Blast it!
E-Excuse me!
Sir Rio...
Sir Rio! It's you, isn't it?
I've spent all this time wanting to apologize!
All this time... I've wanted to thank you.
For what?
For the past. For what
happened at the academy.
You rescued me from danger,
but I wasn't able to say thank you.
Even worse, you were subjected
to groundless suspicions...
and you left the academy because of it.
Princess Flora, I can think of no
reason that I should receive thanks
or apologies from you.
Do you find it burdensome?
Not at all.
But if you are so generous
as to have ever wanted to bestow
thanks or apologies upon me,
then I ask that you please forget the
name of the person you speak of as Rio.
That alone is more than enough.
I see.
I-I'm sorry! I've misunderstood and
asked you such strange questions!
I'm sorry, but I can't admit that I'm him.
I will take you back to the mansion.
Thank you.
Thanks to the two of you, the damage
was kept to an absolute minimum.
O-Oh! No, we didn't do anything much.
And the situation hasn't been resolved yet.
We should be thinking about what comes next.
You're right. Thank you.
I have some understanding of healing magic.
If you need me, I will help.
That would be wonderful!
If you'd come this way...
What is the situation out there?
Please don't speak, Duke Huguenot.
Lady Liselotte!
Duke Huguenot...
Roanna, explain the situation to them.
Then I will take her place
and continue the healing.
Who are you?
I'm here to help.
Heal.
Monsters attacked us here in this room.
Thanks to Sir Hiroaki's actions,
we managed to make it through,
but Duke Huguenot suffered severe wounds.
Is the Hero all right?
I believe he is merely unconscious.
I see.
How is Princess Flora?
When the monsters attacked us in the gardens,
an unknown man appeared from inside
the mansion with Princess Flora
and fled the grounds.
Wh-What did you just say?
But Sir Haruto is tracking
Princess Flora and the man alone.
Th-Then, wh-when I tried to help
Princess Flora escape...
I never imagined that that man could...
What have I done?
Roanna, you made the best decision
you could in that situation.
Right now, all we can
do is trust Haruto to—
Are you all right, Your Grace?
It's probably best not to
strain yourself too greatly.
No, I can feel the pain rapidly receding.
Your skills are magnificent.
She had already completed the initial
treatment, so I didn't have to do much.
After a little rest, I believe
you will be fully recovered.
Haruto has returned.
What?
Haruto!
I'm sorry for worrying you both.
Don't be.
Welcome back.
Sir Haruto! Princess Flora!
As promised, I have brought
Princess Flora back.
Unfortunately, I allowed
the kidnapper to escape.
Just bringing Princess Flora back...
How can I ever thank you?
Then, may I entrust Princess Flora to you?
Of course.
For the moment, may I ask you to
come with me into the mansion?
As you wish.
Princess Flora, this...
I-I...
I think my legs are frozen from fear.
I'm so sorry.
I understand.
In that case, though I'm being presumptuous,
I will accompany her inside like this.
If you would. Thank you.
We're counting on you, Haruto.
Now, with regard to the kidnapper...
Sir Haruto, did you notice
anything in particular about him?
I do have some idea about his identity.
Or rather, I knew that man.
You did?
Yes. When he appeared at the house...
I realized that I'd heard his voice before.
Then, do you know the man's name?
It's Lucius.
How do you know that man, Sir Haruto?
He's someone entangled with my past.
Entangled with his past?
Forgive me. I didn't mean to
ask something so personal.
Not at all.
It was good medicine, wasn't it?
Your physical injuries are much too severe.
There is no other choice.
After all, I cannot have you die.
B-Blast it! If I... If I'd had my left arm...
I could have won!
Give it up. At your current strength,
there is no way you could have beaten him.
We greatly underestimated
his strength, didn't we?
This time, we should quietly
accept our utter defeat.
From this point forward, we will put
any plans to deal with him aside.
Noninterference is the
best course of action.
What did you say?
You aren't allowed to object.
After all, you were the
weak one in that fight.
Princess Flora!
Roanna.
Princess Flora, I am so glad
you are unharmed.
Please feel free to use this chair.
I'll put you down now.
Yes, thank you.
Haruto, you have my gratitude.
Not at all.
Then we will take our leave.
Let's help those outside.
Yes.
Please, wait!
The attendants I deployed to
other areas have begun to return,
so I ask that all three of
you please rest a little.
I'll have rooms prepared immediately.
That's perfect. We can handle things here,
Liselotte, so you should go, too.
We'll ask Princess Flora about the details.
Thank you.
Then, I will set up a time for
all of us to speak later
so that we can exchange information.
Yes.
Sir Haruto, would you be willing to
come and tell us about what happened?
Of course. That won't be a problem.
I hope that you will allow
me to express my gratitude
for rescuing Princess Flora at that time.
I humbly accept the sentiment. It's more
than enough. Now, if you will excuse us.
Spirit Chronicles 2
Here you go!
It's delicious! It tastes
the same as Haruto's.
I've told you.
That's because I'm Rio's teacher.
Right, Rio?
Rio? Did you hear me?
Yes.
It's just...
Princess Flora... has realized
who I really am.
What? She did?
That's why she looked like that earlier.
What will Princess Flora do?
I asked her to forget the name Rio
and I think she understood, but...
In that case, I don't think
she'll speak of it to anyone.
That's just the sort of person she is.
I'm certain it will be just fine.
All right. If you say so, Professor, then...
But there's a risk in
staying here any longer.
We don't want them to find
out who you are, Professor.
That's true.
So, once the talks with
Miss Liselotte are done,
why don't we head straight back
to the Village of the Spirits?
The Village of the Spirits? I'd like that.
As I mentioned yesterday,
we've learned that Miss Miharu's
friend, Miss Sumeragi Satsuki,
has been summoned to Galarc as a Hero.
I'd like to convey the news to her.
All right.
What about you, Aishia?
I'm fine with it, but...
are you sure, Haruto?
Do you want to go back home like this?
Yes. I'm all right.
Then it's fine.
Is something wrong?
It's...
Yes?
What happened between you and this
Lucius who kidnapped Princess Flora?
You said he was entangled with your past...
But if you don't want to tell me,
that's all right! I was just a little curious.
I'm avenging my mother.
He's the man who killed my
mother right in front of me.
And he may be the person
who killed my father, too.
I-I'm sorry.
I asked about something
incredibly painful, didn't I?
No, I always intended to
tell you if you asked.
I don't ever want to lie to you, Professor.
Only... it's not a very fun story.
I loathe that man,
and I can't ever forgive him.
But I sort of feel like
I've got my answer now.
I decided that I would face things head on,
without running... so I'm all right.
I see.
If possible, I'd be grateful if this
conversation stayed here, between us.
There really are only a few
people who know about it.
Thank you, Rio, for telling me.
But if anything happens, come and
talk to me. I've told you before...
No matter what happens,
I'm on your side, Rio.
I know.
We've learned a few details about
the man who abducted Princess Flora.
You have?
We don't know where he's active right now,
but he was originally born into a
low-ranked noble house in our kingdom.
Did you know this, Haruto?
I wasn't aware of that.
His name is Lucius Orgueil.
He was once a candidate to
become the King's Sword.
He and the current King's Sword, Alfred Emerle,
once fought to surpass each other.
The reason he wasn't chosen as the King's Sword
is that before he could be appointed,
his family's house fell from the nobility.
Then, he kidnapped Princess Flora because
of his deep hatred for the Beltrum Kingdom?
If that's how things went,
his grudge isn't justified.
He's a very petty man.
We haven't determined that
that was his motive yet,
and I can't help wondering
about the other man, Reiss.
Reiss, is it? I believe
I recognize that name.
The ducal house of Arbor was
rumored to have secret connections
to a diplomat from the Proxia Empire.
Though, it's possible that they
simply share the same name.
According to Princess Flora,
he hid his face with a hood.
Sir Haruto, did you see anything?
No, not clearly.
Even if I had seen that diplomat's face,
I'm not sure I could say for certain
whether the two men were one and the same.
Which means that, since we've
confirmed Lucius's identity,
tracking him is our surest path forward.
You're right. I will look into whether
he's had any contact with our forces.
Which means that it will be
necessary to return to Rodania.
Thank you. I will conduct an
investigation on my side as well.
Yes.
And now... Sir Haruto, may I ask
what you plan to do next?
Actually, something urgent has come up,
so I plan to leave Amande for a time.
I see. In that case,
we must take this opportunity
to ready everything we wish
to give you as thanks.
After the monster attack, Lady Liselotte,
both you and the town of
Amande face difficult times.
There is no need to go to
such efforts on my account.
That won't do. Sir Haruto, it's because
you were here that we still are too.
Is there anything you want?
To tell the truth,
I have been struggling to find something
that would convey our thanks.
In that case, I have a
request of Lady Liselotte.
Yes?
If it's at all possible...
could I attend the party in Galarc
where the Heroes will be introduced?
The party where the Heroes
will be introduced?
You mean the evening affair being
held at our royal palace, don't you?
You wish to attend, Sir Haruto?
Yes. My travel companions and I...
wish to meet Dame Sumeragi Satsuki.
A Few Days Later
Morning.
Good morning!
Masato, you overslept again!
Don't keep everyone waiting!
Today, Miharu-oneechan is
making omurice for everyone!
Omurice? For real?
You can eat once you've
washed your face and hands.
Okay!
Thank you!
That might be Onii-chan.
What?
Nice catch!
That was close, Miharu!
Th-Thank you, Sara-chan!
Latifa?
I'll go and welcome him!
Me, too!
Honestly!
Miharu, Aki, why don't we go, too?
Okay!
Onii-chan!
Welcome home, Onii-chan!
I'm back, Latifa.
You seem to be doing well.
I am!
Big Sis Celia, Big Sis Aishia...
welcome home!
We're back.
Master Rio!
Have you all been well, too?
Yes!
Haruto-niichan! Big Sis Celia!
We can speak Strahlian now!
Right, Aki-neechan?
We've got it down pat!
You can leave it to us!
It's true! You're all amazing!
Welcome back.
Thanks to everyone's help, we've gotten
a lot more used to this world.
I'm glad to hear that.
We three have some news
we'd like to tell you, too.
We've learned that Miharu-san's
senpai, Sumeragi Satsuki-san,
has been summoned to the
Galarc Kingdom as a Hero.
Satsuki-san is...
Wow! You found her!
Then what about my brother?
I'm sorry. I don't know where
your and Masato's brother is yet.
I see.
But now that we know that
Satsuki-san is here,
I think it's very possible that your
older brother is in this world, too.
Yes! And he may even be with Satsuki-san!
That's possible, right?
Yes!
A month from now, they're going to hold a
party where they'll introduce Satsuki-san.
I think that it will be
possible for me to attend.
Which is why, if you three would like,
we could all travel to the
Galarc Kingdom together.
For real?
In that case, we should throw a
celebration party for all of you!
We should! After all, they've found
the friend they were looking for!
That's a really big step forward!
Master Haruto, Miss Celia, and
Lady Aishia have all returned.
Today is a wonderful day
full of happy things!
Yes, it is!
It's because I came without eating
Big Sis Miharu's omurice first.
I'll head back first!
Really? Don't eat more than your share, okay?
Onii-chan, let's go home!
Yes.
Haruto-san, I'm so glad.
Thank you for returning unchanged.
H-Haruto-san?
Wait!
Mii-chan...
Haru-kun?
Big Sis Miharu! Onii-chan says
he wants to eat omurice, too!
What? But it's a special occasion,
so I'll make anything you like.
I really love omurice, too.
Just like Haru-kun?
Though, everything you make
is delicious, so I love it all.
Me, too!
And me! I haven't had it in
a while, so I'm very happy!
I'll do my very best!
Thank you for the meal!
Oh, it looks so good! It looks yummy!
It's good, isn't it?
Now entering...
the Hero of the Galarc Kingdom...
Dame Sumeragi Satsuki.
The Hero of Restoration...
Sir Sakata Hiroaki.
The Hero of the Centostella Kingdom...
Sir Sendou Takahisa.
The Hero of the Beltrum Kingdom...
Sir Shigekura Rui.
And also, an honorary knight
of the Galarc Kingdom...
Haruto Amakawa.
What?
Spirit Chronicles 2
Thank you for watching!
Illustration: Minazuki Futago